# YVES ISITE

## SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Texas, Dallas +250-791-457-023 yvesisite@gmail.com

#### PROFILE SUMMARY

I am a professional Software Engineer with 6 years of professional experience as a Frontend developer. I possess strong communication, creative and analytical skills. I'm a good Team player, and I have also served as a Team Lead in several companies across various projects. I'm flexible enough to learn any technology if required at hand.

## SOFT SKILLS

- Problem solving

- Agile Environment

- Project management & Tools

- Open-minded

- Active Listening

- Proper Time management

- Software Career mentoring

- Project and changing requirements adaptability

- Customer Advocate

## TECHNICAL SKILLS

- React.js(6 yrs of Exp.)

- Heroku (6 years)

- Wordpress, AWS (5 years)

- Optimization (5 years)

- SASS, Tailwind CSS

(4 yrs)

- Prisma, Sequelize (3 yrs)

- Web performance (4 yrs)

- Springboot (4 yrs of exp.)

- ExpressJS, Nuxt.js (4 yrs)

- Mongoose, Hibernate (5 yrs)

- Unit Testing (Node.js, Mocha, Chai, Jest) - Docker (3 yrs)

- Node.js (5 yrs)

- Git | Github (7 yrs)

- PostgreSQL (4 yrs)

- PHP, Laravel (6 yrs)

- Next.js (4 yrs)

- MySQL (5 yrs)

- Typescript (3 yrs)

- GraphQL (4 yrs)

- Gitlab (3 yrs)

- Figma (4 yrs)

#### EDUCATION

## Bachelor's Degree in Software Engineering)

Rwanda Coding Academy

**Upper High School (Software Engineering Department)** 

Groupe Scolaire Sainte Bernadette SAVE

2015 - 2018

2013 - 2015

#### WORK EXPERIENCE

## Senior React Developer | Team Lead (Full-time)

Government of Rwanda | Ministry of Education

- Technical Team Lead
- UI development with React.js v18
- Development Team Lead
- Progressive Web App

July, 2019 - Sept, 2022

## Senior Frontend developer | Team Lead (Full-time)

Ejobu

- Server establishment & maintenance
- UI Implementation with React 18, Tailwind & was a PWA
- Database Design
- Technical Team Lead

## Mid - Level FullStack developer (Full-time)

February, 2017 - April, 2017

May, 2017 - June, 2019

Bookinga

- React.js, Dockerization, Node.js, Springboot Developer
- Unit Tester
- Technical Team Lead

## Junior React developer (Part-time)

July, 2016 - January, 2017

ATLP (Andela Technical LP)

- · Backend design with Node.js, Database design and management
- UI Implementation with Angular v14
- Integration with BE

## Frontend developer (Part-time)

March, 2017 - July 2020

SkiDesign

- UI / UX design (Mockup design)
- UI Implementation with React
- · Integration with backend

## AWARDS / OTHER ACHIEVEMENTS

- 2021 best employee in Ministry of Education | Rwanda Hackerrank GraphQL Certificate
- 2019 best employee at Ejobu
- 2015 RCA College best developer
- Hackerrank Advanced React.js Certificate
- Hackerrank Heroku, AWS Certificates

- Ideation, Prototyping Workshop Certificate
- EFSET English Certificate
- TOEFL (English) Certificate

## INTERESTS AND ACTIVITIES

- Problem solving
- Technology
- Travel
- Volleyball
- Chess

#### RECENT PROJECTS

- https://kobra.dev/
- https://expensa.io/
- https://yombi.rw/
- <a href="http://gssbsave.co.rw/">http://gssbsave.co.rw/</a>
- <a href="https://bookinga.rw/">https://bookinga.rw/</a>

## LANGUAGES

**French English** Kiswahili **Kinyarwanda** (Advanced) (Intermediate) (Fluent) (Native speaker)

**PROFILES** 

Github: IsiteYves Linkedin: yves-isite-5779491a3/ Twitter: <u>IsiteYves</u>